I'm pretty sure there's something wrong.
这操作绝对不在线
We're off to a great start.
要找个好感觉捏
Greetings and welcome to LGR Oddware,
大家好 欢迎收看LGR志异
where we're taking a look at hardware and software
在这里 我们将回顾一些怪异的 被遗忘的怪异软硬件
that is odd, forgotten and obsolete.
And this time, we've got this right here.
这回呢 我们来看 Essential Reality P5 手套控制器
This is the Essential Reality P5 Glove controller,
I guess you could call it,
念起来有点拗口
and it's sort of a glorified mouse input device type thing for PCs,
这玩意像是手套形状的电脑鼠标
to let you control games and your computer desktop,
通过你指尖的跃动 你就可以控制游戏和电脑桌面啥的
and whatever else, through the power of your fingers.
It's quite the experience,
用起来 确是一番独特体验
and this was actually given to me at the Vintage Computer Festival Midwest 2019.
实际上 这是我去参加2019年美国中西部古董电脑展时 有人给我的
Forgive me, I didn't write down your name, but he gave me this T-shirt as well.
抱歉 当时没记下你的名字 但他给我了这个T恤衫
I guess he's with Free Geek, Twin Cities.
看样子他是这个组织的一员
They do some cool stuff with e-cycling and all that,
他们做电子回收之类 感谢你们给我这两件东西
thank you for both of these things,
but yeah, he apparently got this dropped off there,
看样子 他一看是我 这玩意也是箱说全 就送给我了
and thought of me, and it's like brand new and everything,
so here it is, thank you very much for giving this to me,
这就是了 十分感谢你们送我这些
and yeah, let's take a look at the P5!
现在我们来看看这个P5手套吧
Alrighty, time to get hands-on with this thing.
好的 该穿上这个玩意了
This is the Essential Reality P5,
这就是 Essential Reality P5
with P5 standing for power of five, as in your five fingers.
P5是Power of Five的缩写 也就是运用你五个手指的力量
It sold for $150 when it launched in the latter half of 2002.
在2002年下半年发售的时候 售价149.99美元
A price that immediately drew criticism.
这价格在当时立刻引发了争议
Sure, it came packed with full versions
虽说这玩意附赠俩游戏的完全版
of the games, Operation Tiger Hunt and Hitman 2,
游戏分别是《盟军行动：猎杀虎王》和《终极刺客2》
注:《终极刺客2》是《杀手2》引进中国时候 发行商起的名字
but 150 bucks?
不过150美元 在当时是和任天堂GameCube游戏机一个价
注：建议收看 BV1eW411Y7pr 喷神评测《霹雳娇娃》游戏 (Gamecube平台)
That was the same price as a brand new
Nintendo GameCube console back then,
so it's little wonder that Essential Reality
怪不得这玩意在2003年初 就降价到99美元了
quickly dropped the price to $99 for the P5 at the beginning of 2003.
"The future is at hand."
广告词还说"未来翻不出你的手掌心"
Ah geez, they couldn't resist a hand pun, huh?
SuperBart: 以下一堆hands的短语，我要疯了，直接deepl解决问题
呃 这玩意连双关都要跟"手"较劲
On the other hand, you've got to hand it to them,
hand sth. to sb.: 将某物给予/依托给某人
话说回来 要宣传出去也只能这样
puns are hands down on the handiest ways
hands down: 无疑地   handiest way: 顺手/方便的方式
要想搞好营销 用好双关语是关键之一
to get a grip on product marketing
without using under-handed business tactics.
而不是搞偷鸡摸狗的勾当
under-handed: 卑劣的
So I give it two thumbs up.
这里我给双份点赞
Anyways, Essential Reality billed the P5
话说回来 这家公司把P5称为终极3D虚拟控制器
as the Ultimate 3D Virtual Controller,
providing six degrees of motion control,
它能够提供六个角度的运动控制
the ability to detect gripping and finger movements.
也能侦测手的抓放 和手指的移动
It drew immediate comparisons to the Power Glove for the NES among gamers,
玩家们立刻将其和NES的Power Glove进行对比
but the mainstream media really latched onto the idea
但是主流媒体把这个想法当作成某种未来鼠标的雏形
of it being a kind of futuristic mouse replacement.
There were all kinds of ridiculous headlines like,
当时有很多标题党 诸如
Are Mice Now Obsolete?
"现在鼠标过时了吗？"
and The Mouse Faces Extinction.
"鼠标要面临灭绝了"
Not to mention calling the P5 a device for hardcore video game players
还有报道说 P5手套是为觉得摇杆和鼠标限制颇多的硬核玩家设计的
that find joysticks and mice too confining.
Because who hates playing games
SuperBart: 就好像没有第二个疯子把Linux当作唯一的日常系统吧233
毕竟没人更比硬核玩家们更讨厌用常规设备打游戏吧:-P
with traditional controls more than hardcore gamers, right?
Now check out this mock-up of the modern day gamer
看看2002年的"现代玩家"搞的什么黑科技
in 2002, complete with a CyMouse head tracker,
有头部跟踪器 头戴显示器 当然 还有我们的手套
Olympus Eye-Trek display, and of course, the P5.
Fantastic!
SuperBart: 什么赛博朋克
好家伙了
The company also touted this as a potential
这家公司还吹嘘说 这玩意在3D建模 CAD绘图和
input device for 3D animation, CAD modeling,
体育模拟方面 作为输入设备很有前景 他们说
and sports simulations, stating that
"there's a lot of people sick of the mouse.
"很多人厌倦了使用鼠标干活
It's a limited two-dimensional device.
毕竟它被限制在二维坐标了
We want to go above and beyond that."
我们要在这基础上更上一层(再加一维)
Indeed, which is why companies like Spacetech IMC
确实 IMC公司在P5手套发售前15年 就发售了SpaceBall设备
sold their Spaceball devices nearly a decade and a half before the P5.
Quite successfully too.
这个很成功
So yeah, they were correct that certain people demanded mouse alternatives.
所以说,确实有很多人想要一个鼠标的替代品
It's just that they were late to the party,
可惜他们入场太晚了
and professionals had long since decided on using devices like the Spaceball,
干活的人们早就开始使用像Spaceball那样的设备了
which left the P5 for quote, hardcore gamers,
所以 这玩意也就只能给那些"不喜欢鼠标和摇杆"的硬核玩家用了
and their supposed hatred of mice and joysticks.
Unfortunate then, that game support was so abysmal.
可惜 在当时 支持该设备的游戏很少
Only five games were officially patched for it.
只有五个游戏有官方补丁支持
The afore-mentioned Hitman 2 and Tiger Hunt,
除了之前提到的《终极刺客2》和《盟军行动：猎杀虎王》之外
as well as Serious Sam II, Black and White,
SuperBart: 我的计组书编写于2011年3月 居然把陈旧的《雷神之锤3》和《英雄萨姆》当作跑分工具:-P
还有《英雄萨姆二次出击》,《黑与白》
Air Lock and a demo for Beach Head 2002.
《AirLock》和《抢滩登陆2002》试用版
Yeah!
挺好
Essential Reality promised more support in the future,
Essential Reality 保证会有更多游戏支持该设备
along with Playstation 2 and X-Box versions,
还会有PS2和XBOX版本 适配左手的型号和小一些的型号
left-handed and smaller-sized models,
and even a fully wireless edition.
甚至会有完全的无线版
Of course, this never happened.
当然 这玩意从来没有搞出来过
Beyond a software update in 2003,
除了2003年的软件更新 他们基本停止开发P5手套
Essential Reality soon stopped development on the P5,
and massively discounted gloves,
大幅度裁剪手套业务
started littering store clearance sections.
这些商品也被当作垃圾一样 被清仓处理了
As fate would have it, though this was when the P5
不过造化弄人 就在此时 P5用户群体终于开始形成了
finally started forming a proper community
with $20 gloves ending up in the hands of hobbyists,
最终 爱好者们花了20美元就买到了这个
who saw the potential with its new low price point.
他们在其价格低谷的时候 看到了它的潜力
Custom drivers and a new API by Carl Kenner were a popular upgrade,
使用Carl Kenner自制的更新驱动和API是比较流行的
soon being preferred by users
在用户中 使用量很快就超过了原版驱动
over the original Essential Reality software.
But yeah, even that's over 15 years old now.
尽管这个设备已经有15年历史了(本视频发行于2019年)
By and large, what little community the P5 once boasted has long since moved on,
总体来说 一开始那点维护P5的小群体早就没了
with recent efforts to add P5 support to OpenHMD having fizzled out.
最近在OpenHMD里集成P5支持的计划也失败了
However, on LGR Oddware, we're just getting started.
不过 在LGR志异中 我们的探索之路才刚刚开始
So, let's see how it was to use one fresh out of the box.
我们拆开这个包装 看看这玩意该怎么用吧
This is the special premiere edition from 2002,
这个是2002年发售的超级无敌至尊版
bundled with unique P5 enabled CD-ROMs for Hitman 2,
专门附带为P5适配的《终极刺客2》
Tiger Hunt and Beach Head 2002.
《盟军行动》和《抢滩登陆2002》的游戏CD
You also get some replacement plastic finger-squeezing thingies,
你还可以得到一些套手指玩意的备用品
and this towering motion tracker they call the P5 Receptor.
和塔状动作捕捉器 他们称其为"P5接收器"
Kind of looks like a slimline computer speaker with a USB cable,
外观像很薄的电脑扬声器 拖着个USB线缆
but in reality, it's an infrared receiver
但实际上 这是个红外接收器 用来接收P5手套发出的移动信息
that senses movement made by the P5 Glove.
So yeah, unlike the Power Glove's ultrasonic microphones,
这和Power Glove使用超声波麦克风接受信息相比 还是不同的
this uses infrared.
Kind of like the Nintendo Wii sensor bar.
有点像Nintendo Wii的接收设备
Finally, there's the glove itself,
最终 就是手套本身 被一堆绳子捆绑在这上面
held in place with far too many twisty-ties here,
but I guess they really wanted to show it off,
我觉得他们要特意展示这个 所以就这么干了
so they did what they had to,
but yeah, here it is!
手套现在拿出来了
It's a combination of plastic and rubber materials
滑进你手的一侧 是塑料和橡胶材质
that slides onto your right hand,
with eight infrared LEDs around the edges,
边缘处接上了八个LED灯
and four buttons on the top left hand side.
在手面的左边 有四个按钮
You know, the P5 Glove is really less of a glove,
看出来了吧 P5手套真的不算是个"手套"
and more of a hand harness that hugs onto your fingers.
更像是挂在你手指上的背带
Actually, you know those jeweled bracelets
实际上 我说的是那种能延伸到手背的宝石手链
that extend to cover your whole hand?
Kind of like that but for obsolete hardware nerds.
和那个有点像 不过是为电子四眼狗设计的
Or perhaps the most ineffective Thanos cosplay,
或者说 是那种最不像灭霸的装扮品
just instead of Infinity Stones, you have infinity LEDs.
不过上面不是永恒宝石 是LED:-P
Anyway, the non-glove has a cable,
话说回来 这个"手套"上面有条线缆 固定在手的最右边
permanently attached to the rear right of the hand,
which connects to the front of the IR Receiver Tower.
与红外接收器的前面相连接
And in return, the tower connects to your PC
接收器通过USB1.1接口 接到电脑上
via USB one point one.
As for where you place the receiver,
至于在哪里放接收器呢
well that's a bit of a thing
我们马上就要面对这档子事了
that we'll get to soon enough,
but yeah, that's about it for setup.
不过呢 配置由此开始了
The rest is all software found on this fourth CD-ROM
盒子底部剩下的 就四张软件CD了
tucked away in the bottom of the box.
The documentation is pretty sparse.
手册内容不多
All you get is this cheap foldout paperwork
就一张廉价的折页纸
that basically just says to plug it in
除了插上完装驱动 啥都没说
and install the software.
So enough of me talking, let's move on
所以此处略过 继续听我说吧
over to more of me talking.
Ahh!
享受.gif
Okay, I've got the Windows XP build going right here,
好了 电脑装上Windows XP 东西也插进去了
and we have the thing plugged in.
All that kind of good stuff.
We've got the hand ready to go,
我们准备好了 现在机器已经启动了
but right now, it is not turned on.
So, I was actually putting it on the wrong way
实际上我第一次插入的时候 我搞错了
when I first got it.
Had to do some adjustments,
得做些调整了
and actually those other plastic things
他们附赠的塑料指环 不仅仅是备用件 而且还更大 这挺好
that it comes with are not only replacements,
but they're a little bit larger, which is good.
Some of my fingers were getting cut off
刚才那指环 搞得我手指有点勒的慌
with the circulation.
Actually, wait, I still did it wrong.
等会 我还是搞错了 应该是这样
It's supposed to go like this.
Then the thumb goes in there,
大拇指放在这里 这玩意绕一圈 与底下接触上
and this goes around and catches onto this bottom part.
Like that? Yeah!
像这样
And now this is the power button.
这个是开关 我们现在开启
So if we turn that on,
you'll see this little red light starts flashing.
我们可以看到 侦测器没找到手套的话 小灯会开始闪烁
If it's not in view, and now it's solid.
现在发现手套了 灯就常亮了
Now it is in view.
As you can see here,
如你所见 它能让鼠标指针移动
it is actually moving the mouse cursor.
Somewhat.
算是吧
Actually, I think I'm going to have to
看样子我得靠后移动一下 这才是最合适的距离
move back a little bit. Yeah.
This is supposedly the optimal distance.
There is however, a calibration
这里呢 有个附带的校准程序 在其右面
thing that it came with, which is this right here.
And yes, I'm using an actual mouse instead of this thing.
没错 我得用真正的鼠标来调出这个:-P
That should give you a clue right there,
这里给了个校准指南 不管了 这里我按下按钮
but anyway, so if I hit the A button.
Dang it!
:-(
This is all part of the experience.
体验如你所见
Okay, if I hit the A button, it clears that out,
好的 我按下A按钮 信号全部清除
and it's supposed to be
然后应该是在校准我得手指移动
calibrating my finger movements.
Come on now!
翻译君正在执行./configure --enable-oral=yes...
There it is!
Okay, now, supposed to squeeze,
现在我们收缩手指
and then press A again, and now, it is calibrated.
然后再按下A键 现在已经被校准了
So index finger is left-click.
现在食指动相当于按左键
As you can see here, I can click like
如你所见 我可以随便点点点 挺好
Click click click clicking around.
That's fine!
And you can switch these around in this menu here,
这里有个菜单 可以更改这些选项
so index left-click, middle finger...
食指是左键 中指是......
Or middle click is the thumb.
中键(滚轮)是大拇指来模拟
And right-click is the middle finger,
右键由中指来模拟
so dunk, over there!
来在这点一下 那点一下啥的
Click and then, whatever.
Anyway, so this is desktop mouse mode.
好的 这就是桌面鼠标模式了
However, as you can see,
不过你也看到了 这玩意没那么可靠
it is not the most reliable thing.
There's definitely a lot of acceleration
在一些坑爹的死区里 有很多的无端加速
in this crazy weird little dead zone,
and as you can see there,
再看看这 都找不到信号了
now it's kind of losing the tracking.
It's constantly losing the tracking.
这玩意经常找不到北
In fact, let me show a brief little video,
说到这 我给大家放个视频片段
or part of a video that it played
whenever I first started this thing up
这个视频在安装完驱动 第一次启动时播放
and installed the software.
- Congratulations on purchasing your P5!
- 恭喜你拥有了P5重力手套
The red LED on the receptor should be facing you,
接收器上的LED灯应当面向你
and it will blink when the glove is out of range.
当手套超出其侦测范围时 它会闪烁
Place the receptor to the right
请将接收器放在显示器 或电脑的右侧
of your monitor or computer.
Facing towards you about one and a half
接收器距离你的手有半米到六十公分远
to two feet away from where you'll be resting your hand.
You can go up to three feet and still get excellent results.
不过就算距离一米 效果仍令人满意
Just move your hand around in the direction you want to go.
将手沿你所要运动方向运动即可
The P5 allows you to go left, right, up, down and z,
P5手套可以侦测上下 左右 和前后的移动
as well as yaw, pitch and roll.
也可以侦测上述三个方向的反转
Point and click, and you're good to go.
真正做到指哪里 点哪里
- So yeah, that shows you how it's supposed to work,
- 好的 以上是这玩意本应工作的样子
and honestly, it seems to be doing what it's supposed to,
说真的 看上去还真的是这样 就是没那么好
it's just not good.
If I were to open up Solitaire here,
这里我打算打开纸牌程序
okay you kind of have to move your hand back
得 你得把手往后移动
and come on, click!
然后给老子点上啊
Click! There we go!
点上啊 这回听话了
Clicking is not the most accurate,
虽然点击模拟没那么准确 也没那么可靠 但确实能用
not the most reliable thing, but it can be done.
And it's totally possible to play
拿这个确实可以玩纸牌:-P
a game of Solitaire on here.
I actually played one to completion earlier,
我之前确实拿这个玩了一局 然后受了点伤
and caused some harm to myself.
Take a look at my index finger there.
看我的中指 已经上创可贴了
I've got a bandaid on there,
because look at this footage from earlier.
这是我之前的录像片段
It actually started wearing off the skin from my knuckle.
这已经开始擦破我指关节的皮了
Because I was clicking.
因为当时我好像一直点击了有15分钟
Just clicking, maybe 15 minutes worth,
and it just rubbed the skin right off of there,
然后这玩意开始擦破我这里的皮了
so that's a thing.
It is just rubber here after all,
虽然就是个橡胶 当然 这玩意做工也没那么精细
I mean it's not like the most abrasive rubber.
It's not super soft, but they should've put
这个没那么软 他们当时应该在这底下放个垫的玩意
some of the coating on the bottom there too.
Maybe prevent that, but anyway,
也许能避免这个情况 不过玩纸牌确实够了
that's enough Solitaire.
Let's, oh no, here we go!
接下来......等会 现在行了
Ahh, hitting little buttons and any kind of thing
看上去这玩意 不是用来点击十分小的按钮的:-P
like that is not what this is made for.
Come on, go down there!
给我下来
Now see, this is a challenge.
看见了吗 这算是个挑战
Sometimes getting all the way over to the start menu
有时要把指针一路拉到开始菜单 会很难
is a real big thing.
I just want to go down there.
我得如此地甩胳膊到这里
That time it worked.
这回可以了
If I move all the way back here,
如果我一路这么动 也能用
it kind of works.
Actually I'm about three feet away here.
实际上 我的手离接收器有一米
Ahh!
:-\
- You can go up to three feet and still get excellent results.
- 不过就算距离一米 效果仍令人满意
And still get excellent results.
效果仍令人满意
Excellent results.
令人满意
E X C E L L E N T  R E S U L T S
令 人 满 意.flac
- Anyway, come on!
- 不管了 找一下指针在哪里
Figure out where I am, there we are!
We can open up something like Air Lock.
我们现在启动Air Lock 算是个演示程序
This is a little demo of a thing.
What? P5 authenticate failed?
嘛玩意 P5设备认证失败 彳亍口巴 我们再试一次
Oh, that's good!
Let's try that again.
Hey, it worked that time.
好家伙 现在可以了
All right, so you've got this cage,
现在你操控这个笼子 然后移动它来收集这一堆C60类似物
and you're supposed to move it in and out here,
and grab these floating objects, and that's it.
Remember glove ball?
有点像接扔过来的沙袋
Yeah, this is not a very well-made demo,
虽说这个演示本身制作的不算精良
but it does work just about better than
但它的手感 确实比我测试过的其他软件强多了
anything else that I've tried.
Because that's actually made for
因为这个确实是为P5手套设计的
this particular P5 in mind,
it's not just some, this works great.
而不是随便适配的 所以工作良好
Come on! There we go!
好的 就这样
Wow, that was amazing.
哇 成绩够高的
And that's all this is, you just try to
这游戏就这样 随便摆两下就行
[laughs] it's literally a game that
这玩意就是告诉你 这玩意操控很灵敏
shows off how finicky this thing is.
It's like how quickly can you fight the controls,
看看你的操控够不够快 能不能达到你所想
and actually make it do what you want?
And it does that every time you try
然后呢 每次你要关掉它 或是最小化的时候
to knock out the game, or close out the game.
Just donk, and you're knocked back to the desktop.
都会报个错 把你扔回桌面
Anyway, another one it comes with that doesn't work is
接下来给大家演示附带的《抢滩登陆2002》 同样也无法工作
Beach Head 2002.
Now the game starts up, usually,
通常来说 游戏能启动 你点击"开始游戏"没问题
so you can just hit Play.
The thing is, it takes you to this thing.
不过呢 他会把你带到这个界面 说:"感谢安装
It's like, thank you for installing.
This game has been enabled with ActiveMark,
本游戏启动了ActiveMARK功能 允许你运行演示版
allowing you to run the demo
and purchase the full version
并购买完整版 而不用再下载一遍"
without having to download again.
In other words, it's a cut down version of the game,
也就是说 这是个阉割版游戏 也就是个演示版
which we knew, it's listed as a demo,
but just click Start Playing,
不过按完"开始游戏"之后 就会这样 屏幕一片空白
and it always just does this.
It goes blank screen.
And yeah, it's just not working.
自然 这啥也干不了
And then it'll take you back to the main menu,
然后你就回到了主菜单 什么欲拒还迎
which is nice, it's oh good!
Now I can check out the controls, like P5 controls.
不过 可以查看控制选项 比如P5控制器选项
It is a custom version of the game.
这是个特制版
If you can click on anything, dang it!
如果你要点击其他东西的话......(孩子又不听话了)
Come on now!
The clicking seems to be not very sensitive in this game.
看样子这玩意没有那么敏感
Here we go!
(孩子喜怒反复无常)
So you can look at the mapping.
你可以看看键位对应
And look, controls, this is going to be great.
看看啊 这控制选项 绝对会很好玩
You can shoot with your thumb,
你可以用大拇指开枪 食指切换武器 中指发射导弹
and toggle weapons with your index finger.
Fire missiles with your middle finger.
Dude that's so cool!
这么玩好酷啊
Hey, let's just play.
现在咱开始玩吧
Let's play.
And it takes you back to this screen again.
然后又是回退到开始屏幕
Okay fine, let's start play.
行吧 现在该行了吧
And you get this, again.
得 又是这样
And it's an endless loop of it trying to
这个激活界面简直是死循环
activate the game, or let you play the demo,
给你玩试用版 不行 想激活吧 也不行
but it doesn't let you do that.
Every time you hit New Game, or Continue Game,
每次点击"新游戏" 或"继续游戏"啥的 都是这玩意
or whatever, it takes you back to this.
Anyway, it doesn't work, the point being,
行 我不管你这熊孩子了
that sucks!
And it also crashes.
而且这玩意也玩崩溃
Everything that it comes with, crashes.
基本附带的东西都要崩溃 真是很频繁啊
Pretty constantly, oh my word!
All right, another one that it comes with
好吧 再来看一个工作得不太好的......什么图标这是233
that doesn't really work... seeing a pattern?
Tiger Hunt.
《盟军行动》
Let's just open that with the normal mouse.
用普通鼠标打开吧:-P
You can see, the menu looks pretty much the same.
如你所见 这界面和刚才的基本类似
There's a P5 section in the options menu.
选项菜单里有个P5选项 有这些东西
So these are your things.
Good luck trying to change any of this though,
不要用手套更改这些选项 真的很难啊
with the actual glove, it's so hard to even,
like I'm barely moving my hand.
我的手基本没动 啊～
Ugh!
Why didn't they redo the menus or anything
为啥他们没有为手套专门重置 或优化一下这个菜单呢
to make this more optimized for the glove?
I don't know.
不管了 开玩!
Let's just play.
We'll not do the training missions.
我们不做新手任务
Come on now!
(三天不打 上房揭瓦是吧)
Oh my word!
Here we go!
Hit the Play button, again this tiny little button
点击屏幕底下的"游戏"按钮 怎么又是小按钮
at the bottom of the screen.
And I'm pretty sure there's something wrong.
我觉得这玩意绝对有问题
You're supposed to be able to control
你应该是通过手的旋转和移动 来控制方向啥的
certain directions and what not by rolling,
and moving around, here we can go into first person.
我改成第一人称吧
It does work, to a degree, here I am shooting,
确实有在工作 我在射击中
but as you can see, there's graphical glitches.
不过画面渲染故障了 绝对有问题
There's something wrong.
We're off to a great start.
真的不是个好开端
So there's something going on with the graphics.
画面渲染绝对有问题
But other than that, you can kind of see
不过除去那些问题 你应该可以看到这玩意是如何工作的
how it's supposed to work, sort of.
You know, moving up and down to aim.
也就是上下移动来瞄准 旋转手臂来四处转动
Rotating your arm is supposed to move you around.
There's a way you can WASD it too,
你也可以按WASD键来移动 手臂四处转动 不过手不能离得太近
and sort of move around, but again,
you can't be too close, well there's that.
You can't be too close to the sensor.
你不能离侦测器太近
It doesn't work, but yet, you're supposed to also
这下他罢工了 好吧 你还得用键盘做一堆事情 这可不太好
use the keyboard for a lot of functions.
That's not great.
It constantly thinks I'm rolling.
游戏一直认为我在摇摆胳膊
You can see the steering wheel thing.
看到那个方向盘了吗 我觉得那应该是取材自老款丰田啥的
It's like it's from an old Toyota or something.
I guess that's what you steer tanks with in this game.
我觉得在游戏里 坦克里面都有丰田的方向盘
A Toyota steering wheel.
All right, let's get out of here.
好吧 赶紧逃离这里
Go!
润！
That one at least doesn't crash,
行 直接回到桌面 没有崩溃 挺好
and it goes straight back to the desktop.
That's good!
Now here's one of the more interesting ones.
现在给大家看一个十分有意思的 也是我最想玩的《终极刺客2》
Or ones that I was most interested in trying, Hitman 2.
Cause I'm like how can they possibly
我想知道 他们是如何把潜行游戏适配到P5手套的呢？
take this stealth game and make it work with the P5?
The short answer is, they didn't.
简单来说 没这么做
Right, so Hitman 2.
好的 启动《终极刺客2》
We do at least have some finer control over the mouse here.
这里操控指针 至少比之前顺滑
This is the most promising thing yet.
目前来说算是个好兆头
You see how it's smoothed?
看看这顺滑体验
And I can actually sort of move it where I want it to.
可以说是 我滑到哪里 指针就滑到哪里
Oh no, go back!
不行 返回
This overly dramatic music for this is pretty appropriate.
SuperBart: 五共片头曲即视感233
这戏剧音乐放这里还挺合适
We'll see if it actually loads this time,
我们看看它到底加载不加载游戏
last time I tried to play this, it crashed.
上回搞的时候 它崩溃了
Oh no, it did load it, okay good!
天哪 居然加载了 很好啊
So effectively, you're just controlling
实际上 你只是在控制代号47的视角 估计也就这样了
the view of Agent 47 here.
I'm pretty sure that's it.
You can interact with some things,
你可以和一些东西有互动
again you have to do this weird thing
再一次地 你的手退后到这里 会发生奇怪的事情
where your hand is back here.
You're controlling the movement like this
你得用键盘来控制移动
with the keyboard.
Okay, I forget what button it is.
好吧 我忘了要按哪个按键了
It's one of these fingers.
应该是其中一个手指吧
Come on, open the door!
同志 快开门啊 *3
Open the door, Agent!
Tap! Open the door!
There it is!
好的 虽然不知道怎么搞的 但确实开了
I opened it, I don't know how, but I did.
There's a person.
这里有一个人
How am I doing?
我在干啥？ 老兄 我啥也控制不了啊
I can't control anything, sir.
Everything else, you got to be doing with the keyboard,
剩下的东西呢 你得用键盘控制 体验真不算很愉快
and well, it's uncomfortable to say the least.
Anyway, so we've exhausted everything that it comes with.
好的 附带的东西就先这样 到此结束！
That's it!
Actually, let's try Paint.
这回呢 我们打开画图
So there's something that it is not very good with.
好像拖放功能做的并不好
That is clicking and dragging.
Like when you hold it down, it doesn't want to do--
如果你想往下拽 它好像并不会......
There you go!
好的
It doesn't want to do movement anymore.
貌似又不听话了
So you have to move it a lot.
所以你得大幅度移动
And do like, it's the same problem
然后呢 刚才玩纸牌时遇到的问题又出现了
I was having playing Solitaire.
There we go!
好极了 现在写R 加油！
And now for the R, come on now!
That worked better that time.
现在工作良好
Yeah, perfect!
好极了
There's a learning curve to this, obviously,
很明显 这玩意有学习曲线
but I've been using this thing for hours,
我用这玩意有几个小时了 现在感觉顺手了
and it's just not getting much better.
Man, you should've see it when I first started this.
你们确实应该看看我一开始使用时候的样子
I wish I was recording that, but it was so much worse.
我真希望能当时录下来 当时用的真的太差了
So here's a test that should be stupid.
最后来点搞笑测试
Duke Nukem 3D!
玩《毁灭公爵3D》
We go around here and control things with the mouse.
我们用鼠标模拟模式来四处移动 控制东西
Honestly, considering how limited this game is
说真的 考虑到这玩意用鼠标来玩的诸多限制 这玩意还算行
with the mouse anyway, this is not too bad.
Now one thing I was kind of disappointed in,
这里我觉得有点失望了
was the fact that I saw a lot
我之前看到有人这么搞 把手搞成枪的形状
of the promo shots, saying you could do this,
Like finger guns.
Which you can, but that also means
你确实可以这么搞 但你不能四处观看了
you can no longer look around.
Because you're not only
因为为了这个手型 其他的按键都"按"了下去
pressing other buttons down here to make that shape,
but if you're sideways, it's not going to be
你要把手侧过来的话 看上去它不太乐意走来走去
happy to move around.
But I think it's mostly cause you're pressing other buttons.
我觉得应该是手指大多蜷缩(同时按下按键)的锅
I think middle finger opens doors.
我觉得中指开门 还真是
Sure does.
Nice!
好枪法
Look this way, other way, other way!
看那里 看那里 看那里啊
Oh, he's teleporting away.
得 被传送走了
Come on now, come back!
快回来 快回来
Uh no! No!
啊不
I got this!
(公爵声线)我做到了
Oh no I don't!
我没有/要哭了
Look the other way, Duke!
战友 看另一侧啊
Look down!
往下看啊
Phew! All right!
哈 好了 我们搞定了
We got this!
I really did!
(公爵声线)我可是强强滴
Come on now!
来吧
Ugh! Okay!
呃 好吧
Come on now!
加油啊
Look down!
往下看！
Ugh!
啊～
Well, that's the P5 Glove.
好吧 P5手套演示到此结束
Aw man, feels so gross right now too.
我去 胳膊好酸啊
I've got glove hand, look at that!
看我戴手套的手 全都是红印子 绝对是手套搞得
I got the red marks and everything.
Digs in there!
It is definitely made for hands a little smaller than mine.
这手套绝对是给手比我小的人戴的
That is what it is, the P5 Glove everyone.
这就是P5手套了 同志们 什么玩意这是
What a joke!
Well, that's about it for the
好的 这就是Essential Reality出品的P5手套了
P5 Glove by Essential Reality.
It is not the most enjoyable thing to use in practice.
实际用起来没那么愉快
The idea is much more interesting
这玩意也就图一乐 认真用就算了
than the actual experience,
but nonetheless, I'm amused by this thing.
无论如何 玩起来还是很欢乐的
I'm glad it exists and I was glad
这玩意存在挺好 我能体验一下也是很高兴
to have the opportunity to take a look at it.
However, it is really just disappointing in the end.
不过 最终还是很失望
Even knowing its limitations going in,
尽管这玩意限制颇多 我最终还是很失望
I still somehow ended up disappointed.
Yeah, that's just kind of how it goes with all of these
和我之前用过的虚拟手套基本很相似
virtual gloves that I've used.
I've messed with the Valve Index more recently,
我最近在玩Valve Index(V社的虚拟设备)
it's interesting to have that kind
尽管手指跟踪功能很有趣 但是仍然没有那个味道
of a finger tracking thing, but even that's
still not quite where I want it yet.
It's like when is this ever going to get to
怎么说呢 用输入设备 真的能做到完美模拟到达一个地方的感觉吗
a place where this actually makes sense
as an input device?
Gloves, maybe never!
手套先去死吧
It's neat to see all the steps along the way for sure.
当然 看到技术一路进化 确实很好
Although I did actually try,
尽管我为了完整体验 我确实尝试过
for the sake of completeness,
those custom drivers and API things
使用爱好者当时自制的驱动和API
that were made for it back in the day.
And they do improve it somewhat with certain things.
他们确实改善了一些东西
It's not really so much a full driver replacement,
不过不太算是官版驱动替代品
such as it is a library, or set of libraries,
SuperBart: 类比一下 闭源AMDGPU-PRO驱动实际上是跑在开源AMDGPU上面的
比如说 这玩意算是一个跑在官版驱动上面的库
that just goes on top of what
Essential Reality provided,
and improves the input on certain things,
提升一些输入方面的提升
like Hitman and Tiger Hunt were a little bit smoother
比如《终极刺客》和《盟军行动》四处观望的时候
to look around, and what not in relative mode.
略微流畅了一些 相对控制模式也是这样
There's absolute mode possibilities as well.
当然 也有绝对控制模式
Certain other things though,
那就得另说了 比如抓沙袋游戏啥的
like that ball-grabbing game or whatever it is,
that was actually worse, I thought,
我觉得用新驱动更差了
with those new drivers,
and it's also not going to affect or improve
我觉得新驱动完全没有改善桌面鼠标移动功能
desktop mouse movement mode at all,
cause apparently, that's just built
毕竟这是写死在硬件的功能:-P
SuperBart: 我觉得应该是写死在底层驱动的功能 不过字幕确实写的是硬件
into the hardware itself.
And it relies on Window's input drivers
而且它还跟Windows的USB输入驱动有关 就这样
for mouse USB stuff, and that's about it.
So it really doesn't do much in terms of
所以我觉得 改进驱动并没有跟我想的一样 提升使用体验
improving the experience for when I hoped
that maybe it could do,
but that's just kind of how it goes.
不过这玩意也就这样子了:-P
It's one of those devices that was really intriguing,
这样的设备真的很有意思
because of course, you see these kinds
毕竟你看到手套本身就很有趣了
of gloves and what not.
VR gloves were always this thing that seemed
VR手套能让一件东西变得看上去是可行的
like it could be possible.
You saw it in movies like "Jurassic Park",
你看《侏罗纪公园》里 有个科学家通过手套操控 操控DNA啥的
that one scene where the scientist is looking around
and messing with DNA or something,
and also "Minority Report",
《少数派报告》电影里也有手套
yeah, there were gloves there.
You know, I guess Spielberg has a thing for VR gloves.
我觉得斯皮尔伯格导演对VR手套有独到见解
Anyway, this is not that, is what I'm trying to say.
不过要我说 根本就不是电影那样
And that's unfortunate, but you know,
虽说有点可惜 不过我觉得这玩意不太可能实现
I guess I didn't really have any expectations
of that being the case either.
Still, it's an interesting device to mess with,
不过使用设备本身还是很欢乐的
and the hobbyist scene is kind of one of those things
在其降价后 那点爱好者的努力也让这一切更有些价值了
where it made a little more sense,
once it got cheaper.
It kind of reminds me of the X-box Connect, in that sense.
说到这 我想到XBOX Connect了
You know, even the Wiimote and the Playstation Move,
还有 Wiimote 和 Playstation Move
when hardware hackers got a hold of it,
当硬件大佬拿到这个 开始自己写驱动的时候
and started writing their own software.
There were some interesting things that were done,
会出现比官版驱动更有趣的东西
that were actually more interesting
than the official software for it.
There's a couple videos on YouTube of this.
油管上有几个相关视频
Some people taking them apart and improving them,
有人拆开设备 改造他们
or one guy even uses it like a midi,
甚至有人把这个改造成类似MIDI音源啥的
I think it's an oscillator or something,
里面应该是有个震动马达啥的
he's doing it like a virtual theremin.
他好像是改造成了特雷门琴
There's some interesting ideas.
好多新奇的主意
But it's not the thing you want to actually use,
不过这可不是你日常会使用的东西
in your day to day.
It is what it is, and that is the P5 Glove.
就是这样 以上就是P5手套了
And that is LGR Oddware.
也是本期LGR志异的结尾了
本视频由SuperBart翻译 原作者LGR发布于2019年10月25日
赞助原作者：https://www.patreon.com/LazyGameReviews
字幕下载： https://github.com/BenderBolg/Subtitles
上传给LGR：https://github.com/BenderBolg/LGR_Chinese_Subtitle
翻译的博客：https://www.superbart.xyz
And if you liked this episode of Oddware,
你要喜欢本期志异视频的话
then perhaps you'd like to check out
也许你会对B站上搬运的其他LGR志异视频感兴趣
some of the others that I've done in the past,
as well as who knows what else.
还有一些其他的视频
I do a whole lot of things here in LGR,
我在LGR上会制作很多东西的
with new videos uploading every week.
油管每周都会更新
And as always, thank you very much for watching.
最后一如既往 感谢大家收看